Encounters are mysterious! But cases are even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والقضايا تلفّها طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today is the pottery case solution!
!اليوم جزء الختام لقضيّة الفخّاري
There are no cracks in Conan's logic!
!لا تصدّعات هناك في استنتاج كونان
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Kikuemon-san, a potter and living national treasure,
قام كيكويمون-سان، الفخّاري الشهير ،والمعروف بالكنز الوطنيّ الحيّ
invited me, Ran, and the old guy to his home in West Tama.
بدعوتي أنا وران والعمّ إلى منزله في تاما الغربية
Before long, an incident occurred!
لم يمض وقتٌ طويل حتّى وقعت حادثة
Masuko-san broke Kikuemon-san's latest work, the Fusui-maru!
كسرت ماسوكو-سان آخر أعمال كيكويمون-سان المعروف بفوسوي مارو في المستودع
That night, during a get-together, Masuko-san became very drunk.
في تلك الليلة، ثملت ماسوكو-سان بشدّة أثناء حفلة
The following morning in the storeroom...
...وفي الصباح التالي، في المستودع
...she was hanged to death!
!وجدناها مشنوقةً
"The Famous Potter Murder Case (Part 2)."
جريمة قتل الفخّاري الشهير (الجزء الثاني)
Were you really all together in the stateroom?
أكنتم جميعاً في غرفة المعيشة حقّاً؟
Y-Yes. The only one who left was Otani, who went to wake her.
أ-أجل، من غادر كان أوتاني فحسب الذي ذهب لإيقاظها
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
Don't tell me you pretended to wake her and hung her in her sleep!
أيمكن أنّك تظاهرت بالذهاب لإنقاذها وشنقتها في نومها؟
N-No! I was only gone for a moment!
!لـ-لا! غبتُ للحظةً فقط
Her room is only two over from the stateroom!
!تبعد غرفتها بغرفتين عن غرفة المعيشة فحسب
Is this true?
أهذا صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
I think he was gone for less than ten seconds.
أظنّه غاب لأقلّ من 10 ثوانٍ
He couldn't have done anything in such a short time...
يستحيل أنّه قام بشيء في ذاك الوقت الوجيز
Did anyone else leave?
أغادر أحدٌ آخر؟
Well, I left for a short moment to call her.
غادرتُ قليلاً للاتّصال بها
We thought she had gone somewhere.
ظننا أنّها قد خرجت
I didn't really leave, though;
،لكنّي لم أغادر حقّاً
I only called her cell phone from the phone in the connecting hallway.
فقد اتّصلتُ بهاتفها الخلويّ من الهاتف في الرواق أمام غرفة المعيشة
That's strange. She's not answering.
غريب، إنّها لا تجيب
Cell phone? Hers?
هاتفها الخلويّ؟ لديها واحد؟
That's right. I had Masuko-san always carry a cell phone.
أجل، طلبتُ من ماسوكو-سان حمل هاتف خلويّ دوماً
She was in charge of everything else,
فقد كانت تتولّى كلّ المسؤوليات الأخرى
so that we could focus on making our works.
بحيث نستطيع التركيز على صنع أعمالنا
What is "everything else"?
المسؤوليات الأخرى؟
Things like business transactions and scheduling exhibitions.
مثل عمليات بيع القطع وجدولة المعارض
So our master very rarely goes anywhere.
لذا كان معلّمنا لا يغادر معظم الوقت
But that's odd. We didn't find a cell phone by her body.
لكنّ ذلك غريب، لم نجد هاتفاً خلويّاً بجوار جثّتها
Oh, a cell phone was found in the victim's room.
بخصوص الهاتف الخلويّ، فقد وجدناه في غرفة الضحيّة
It was apparently under her futon...
...حسناً، كان تحت فراشها وفقما يبدو
Under her futon?
تحت فراشها؟
She always put it under her pillow and used it as an alarm clock.
كانت تضعه تحت وسادتها دوماً وتستعمله كساعة تنبيه
The cell phone was apparently turned off.
يبدو أنّ الهاتف الخلويّ كان مُطفأً
I see. So that's why a call from just the other room wouldn't be heard.
فهمت، لذا لم يصدر صوت رغم أنّ الاتّصال أُجري بالقرب
So, did anyone else leave the room?
إذاً، أغادر شخصٌ آخر الغرفة؟
No, no one else.
...كلا، لا أظنّ
No one...
...لم يغادر
Not that I know of.
أيّ أحد
Then who could have carried her in here and killed her?
من حملها إلى المستودع وقتلها إذاً؟
Assuming she was found right after she was hanged,
بافتراض أنّ العثور على الجثّة كان ،بعد تعرّضها للشنق مباشرةً
everyone has an alibi of being in the stateroom.
حيث كان الجميع في غرفة المعيشة ولديهم حجج غياب
That's what I'm saying! It was a suicide!
!لذا أخبرتك أنّه انتحار! انتحار
Her feet were bare because she was upset and about to kill herself,
كانت قدما السيّدة حافيتين لأنّها كانت متضايقةً وعلى وشك قتل نفسها
and her feet weren't dirty because she used the stepping stones
ولم تتسّخ قدماها لأنّها استعملت المواطئ الحجرية
between the house and the storeroom.
بين المنزل والمستودع على الأرجح
Plus, she had broken the Fusui-maru in this storeroom.
كما أنّها كسرت فوسوي مارو في هذا المستودع
I can imagine her seeing the storeroom when she woke up
أستطيّع تصوّر استيقاظها صباحاً وتوجّهها للمستودع
and walking in without too much thought.
والنظر فيه بلا تفكير
That's true. The rope was used in this storeroom for packing things.
معك حقّ، كنّا نستعمل ذاك الحبل في المستودع لربط الأشياء
Plus we all heard the pot break at the same time.
كما أنّنا سمعنا صوت تحطّم الإناء في الوقت نفسه جميعاً
In any case, we won't make any progress
بأيّ حال، لن نحقّق أيّ تقدّم
until we examine the storeroom in more detail.
حتّى نفحص المستودع بدقّة أكثر
I ask that you all wait in the stateroom for the time being.
أطلب منكم الانتظار في غرفة المعيشة لبعض الوقت
Please don't do anything without permission.
ولا تقدموا على أيّ تصرّف بلا إذن رجاءً
Suicide? Is that really what it was?
انتحار؟ أكان كذلك حقّاً؟
Still, too many things are out of the ordinary.
...لكن هناك أشياء كثيرة غريبة
The open cut on her right leg...
...الجرح المفتوح على ساقها اليمنى
Her unusual lack of footwear and the clean bottoms of her feet...
وتصرّفها الغريب بعدم انتعال شيء وبقاء أخمصيّ قدميها نظيفين
And...
...كما
...this marble I found by the broken Fusui-maru the day before...
الكرة الرخامية التي وجدتُها بجوار ...فوسوي مارو المكسور في اليوم السابق
And what's the other thing?!
وما ذاك الشيء؟
Something I saw at the scene of the crime is bugging me!
...هناك ما أثار حيرتي عندما رأيته في مسرح الجريمة
Alright, you!
!أنت
Oh, just a marble.
ماذا؟ كرّة رخامية فحسب
Only kids would be interested in junk like that.
لا يهتمّ بهذه الأشياء إلّا الأطفال
Oh no!
!تبّاً
Gimme a break, old guy!
ما الذي تفعله يا عمّ؟
Huh?! What the--?!
...ماذا؟ ما الذي
Hold on, Conan-kun! Where do you think you're going?! Stop!
!تمهّل يا كونان-كن، من أين تدخل؟ توقّف
What's that?
ما ذلك؟
Lipstick?
أحمر شفاه؟
I didn't put it there...
...لم أكن من وضعته
What is lipstick doing here?
لمَ يوجد أحمر شفاه هنا؟
Wait a minute!
...أيمكن
H-Hold on!
!تـ-تمهّل
Where are you going, Conan-kun?!
أين تذهب يا كونان-كن؟
The thing that bugged me...
...ما كان يحيّرني
Could it be?!
...أيمكن أنّه
What is it?
ماذا؟ ما الأمر؟
I forgot something.
نسيتُ شيئاً
Maybe so, but you can't just barge in here.
ولو فعلت، لكن لا يمكنك الدخول هكذا
Huh? Where's the lady's body?
ماذا؟ أين جثّة العمّة؟
Taken to the police hospital.
نقلناها لمشفى الشرطة
Yes! This is it!
!وجدتُها! هذه هي
I finally found a trace that the killer failed to hide!
وجدت الأثر الذي فشل القاتل !في إخفائه أخيراً
The fact it's here means that up above is...
...وجوده هنا يعني أنّ في الأعلى
Just as I thought!
كما ظننت
Using this method, you wouldn't need to be in the room to kill her!
باستعمال هذه الطريقة، يمكن ارتكاب الجريمة !دون الحاجة للتواجد في الغرفة حتّى
But to ensure she would die, it would have to be around there...
لكن للتيقّن من نجاح الجريمة، لا بدّ من ...تواجد ذاك الشيء بالقرب
Alright!
!حسناً
H-Hey! What are you doing! Come down!
!أ-أنت! ما الذي تفعله؟ انزل
I told you, I'm looking for something I forgot!
!أخبرتكم أنّي أبحث عن شيءٍ نسيته
We just checked that area, but there was nothing out of the ordinary!
تفقّدنا ذاك المكان للتوّ ولم !نجد شيئاً خارج المألوف
Now come down! It's dangerous!
!ما تفعله خطر، فانزل
Yeah. Doesn't seem to be anything but pottery here...
بالفعل، لا يبدو أنّ هناك شيئاً باستثناء الفخّاريات
Interesting! That's a potter for you!
فهمت، كما تتوقّع من فخّاري
Come down this minute!
!انزل بسرعة
Okay!
!حاضر
Which means one of those two is the killer...
...ما يعني... أنّ المجرم بين ذلكما الاثنين فحسب
...but it's probably that one.
وهو ذاك غالباً
He laid a trap for her and killed her to make it look like a suicide...
...نصب فخّاً للسيّدة وقتلها بحيث يبدو انتحاراً
And only he would still have proof of it on him!
...كما من لا يزال يحمل الدليل عليه
Alright! I know who did it and how!
!حسنٌ، اكتشفت القاتل وحيلته
The question now is how to tell Inspector Megure...
...ما تبقّى هو كيفيّة إخبار المفتّش ميغوري بذلك
Umm, how long do we have to stay in the stateroom?
المعذرة، إلى متى علينا البقاء في غرفة المعيشة؟
Could we get something to eat? We haven't eaten at all today...
أيمكننا الذهاب لجلب طعام؟ فلم نأكل شيئاً منذ الصباح
I'd like to change clothes, too...
أودّ تغيير ثيابي أيضاً
Oh, that should be fine, as long as you tell my men first!
لا أمانع ذلك، طالما تخبرون رجالي أوّلاً
No! If they do that, the evidence'll be gone!
!لا يصحّ! إذا سمحت بذلك فسيختفي الدليل
Evidence?
الدليل؟
Shut up, you stupid kid!
!اخرس أيّها الصبيّ
Dad!
!أبي
Evidence, my butt! This was a suicide! There was no killer!
!أيّ دليل؟ كان هذا انتحاراً !لا قاتل هناك
Right, Inspector?
ألستُ محقّاً يا حضرة المفتّش؟
Y-Yes...
...بـ-بلى
Ouch...
...مؤلم
Guess I'll just have to knock him out with this stun-gun wristwatch...
ليس بيدي سوى تنويم العمّ ...بمسدّس ساعتي بالفعل
Say! I found the thing you were talking about earlier!
اسمع، وجدتُ الشيء الذي كنت !تتكلّم عنه يا عمّ
W-What thing?
ماذا؟ أيّ شيء؟
You don't care if I say it out loud for everyone to hear?
لا تهتمّ إذا أفصحت عنه أمام الجميع؟
Huh?!
!ماذا؟
Here, listen.
أعطني أذنك
As I was saying, earlier, you told me...
...كما قلت، الشيء الذي أخبرتني به
Now I'll just put the button speaker on his collar...
حسنٌ، ألصق مكبّر الصوت الشبيه ...بالزرّ على ياقته
Oh! You found it! Well done!
!رائع! وجدت ذاك الشيء إذاً؟ أحسنت
Hold on. Just what did you find?
لحظة، ما الذي وجده؟
Evidence that the killer failed to hide completely, of course!
الدليل الذي فشل القاتل في إخفائه بالطبع
K-Killer?! Are you saying--?!
...الـ-القاتل؟! أتقصد
Yes. She didn't commit suicide at all. She was murdered.
أجل، لم تنتحر السيّدة، بل قُتلت
By someone here, in fact.
من قِبل أحد موجود هنا في الواقع
Oh! This should be interesting!
!سيكون هذا مثيراً
It's an honor to watch the great Sleeping Kogoro at work firsthand!
!من المُشرّف مشاهدة تحليل كوغورو النائم بأمّ عيني
Mori-kun! If the body was found right after she died,
موري-كن، إذا وُجدت الجثّة بعد موتها فوراً
these people couldn't possibly have done it!
فيستحيل أنّ أحدهم أقدم على قتلها
Besides, you were the one who insisted it was a suicide!
كما أنّك من كان مصرّاً !على أنّه كان انتحاراً
That was a lie meant to throw the killer off guard.
كانت كذبةً لجعل القاتل يستهتر
Because we wouldn't want the evidence to be destroyed, after all.
لأنّنا لا نريد أن يتخلّص من الدليل
Again, just what is this evidence?!
كما قلت، أيّ دليلٍ هذا؟
Blood, Inspector!
!الدم يا حضرة المفتّش
Blood?
الدم
Yeah! Kogoro-ojisan asked me to look for strange blood on the floor!
أجل، طلب منّي العمّ البحث عن بقعة دم غريبة على الأرض
Strange blood?
بقعة دم غريبة؟
See? He must've meant blood like this!
انظر، لا بدّ أنّه كان يقصد هذه البقعة
W-What is this?!
...هـ-هذا
You carried the body over here, right?
أنتما من حملا الجثّة إلى هنا، صحيح؟
Yes. We thought she might still be alive.
أجل، ظننا أنّها قد لا تزال حيّة
I had her arms and Seto had her legs
فحملتُها من ذراعيها، بينما حمل سيتو ساقيها
when we set her down in the corner.
وأنزلناها عند الزاوية
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
Yeah.
بلى
If so, then this really is strange.
في تلك الحالة، فهذا غريبٌ بالفعل
What's the deal with that blood?
أهناك أمرٌ ما بذاك الدم؟
I think blood dripped from the body when we were carrying it...
...أظنّه دماً تساقط أثناء حملنا للجثّة
No, not all of the blood was from then.
كلا، ليس كلّه دماً من حملكما لها
It's hard to tell, since it's mixed with other blood,
تصعب الملاحظة بما أنّه محاط بدمّ آخر
but there's something else here.
لكن يوجد شيءٌ آخر هنا
S-Something else?
شـ-شيء آخر؟
The shape that drops of human blood make
الشكل الذي تتركه قطرات دم الإنسان عند سقوطها على الأرض
is pretty much determined by how far they fall.
يعتمد على الارتفاع الذي تسقط منه غالباً
The farther the fall, the larger the circle,
،كلّما سقطت من ارتفاع أعلى، توسّعت الدائرة
and the more developed the surrounding splatter is.
كما شدّة التلطّخ حولها
If you had carried her by her arms and legs,
،إذا حملتماها من ذراعيها وساقيها
the distance from her toenails to the floor was 50 cm at best.
فستكون المسافة من أظفار أقدامها للأرض 50 سم بأبعد الحدود
However, these blood drops clearly fell more than a meter.
لكنّ بقعة الدم هذه سقطت من ارتفاع يعلو متراً بكلّ وضوح
The fact that such blood is here...
...وجودها هنا يعني
Are you saying she was on top of this shelf?
أتقصد أنّها كانت فوق هذا الرفّ؟
But why?
لكن لمَ؟
Could it be?!
!أيمكن؟
Yes. The killer had carried her to the top of the shelf last night...
أجل، حملها القاتل لأعلى الرفّ ...في غطاء الليل البارحة
...where she slept, with a rope around her neck, tied to the roof beam.
حيث نامت وحبلٌ مربوط حول عنقها متّصل بعارضة السقف
That way, when she woke in the morning, she would lose her balance,
بهذا الشكل، عندما تستيقظ صباحاً، ستفقد توازنها
fall from the shelf, and wind up hanging herself.
وتُشنق بمجرّد سقوطها من الرفّ آلياً
The loud sound right after she was hanged
،الصوت المرتفع الذي أصدرته بعد شنقها بقليل
was from the pots left directly below the noose.
كان من الأواني الموضوعة أسفل أنشوطة الحبل تماماً
Being hanged from that height would result in an almost instant death.
التعرّض للشنق من ذاك الارتفاع سيؤدي للموت الفوريّ تقريباً
The broken pots would then look like a stepstool she had overturned.
ستبدو الأواني المحطّمة عندها مجرّد مواطئ أقدام أطاحت بها
Of course, this was also meant to hasten the body's discovery
كان الهدف من هذا تعجيل العثور على الجثّة بالطبع
and solidify the alibi of the killer inside the stateroom.
وتثبيت حجّة القاتل في غرفة المعيشة
Then what about the cut on her right calf?
ماذا عن الجرح على ربلتها اليمنى أيضاً؟
Look closely at the top of the shelf. Do you see a protruding nail?
،أمعنوا النظر لأعلى الرفّ رجاءً ألا تجدون مسماراً بارزاً؟
Yes, I do.
بلى، صحيح
When she lost her balance and fell, she likely cut her calf on that nail.
،عندما فقدت توازنها وسقطت جرح ذاك المسمار ربلتها غالباً
The blood landed on a different spot on the floor
سقوط الدمّ على موقع مختلف على الأرض
probably because she had held on to the shelf for a few seconds.
هو لتمسّكها بالرفّ لبضعة ثوانٍ على الأرجح
Meaning she just happened to get the cut on her calf?
أي أنّ الجرح كان بالمصادفة؟
Yes. It wasn't part of the killer's plan.
أجل، لم يكن في حسابات القاتل
He was probably quite shocked when he saw her cut.
صعقته الدهشة عندما رآه غالباً
But the killer would've quickly discovered the cause of it,
لكنّ القاتل كان ليدرك سببه فوراً
as well as the blood right by the shelf.
كما الدمّ بجوار الرفّ
Even if the body swung, the shelf would still have been too far away.
حتّى لو ترنّحت الجثّة، وتناثر الدم في المكان فيبقى الرفّ بعيداً جدّاً
Fearing his trick would be figured out if this blood was found,
خشي القاتل أن تُكتشف حيلته ،إذا اُكتشفت بقعة الدمّ هذه
the killer directed the others carrying her body to the blood
فموّه على الجميع، وجعل الجثّة تُنقل لمكان البقعة
to try to hide it with new blood.
لإخفاء الدمّ بدم آخر
Isn't that right, the one who left last night's party
ألستُ محقّاً، يا من غادر ،أثناء حفلة البارحة
to carry her to the storeroom and set up this trick...
...لحمل السيّدة للمخزن ونصب هذه الحيلة
...Seto Ryuichi-san?!
يا سيتو ريويتشي-سان؟
S-Seto?! Don't tell me it was you?!
...سـ-سيتو؟ أيمكن أنّك
Hold on, now! I wasn't the only one who left during the party!
انتظر قليلاً! لم أكن الوحيد الذي !غادر أثناء الحفلة
Besides, why would I do something so daring
كما لمَ قد أُقدم على شيءٍ بهذه الجرأة
with a great detective like you around?!
بتواجد مُتحرٍّ عظيم مثلك؟
You had no other choice.
لم يكن أمامك خيارٌ آخر
Because she had broken the Fusui-maru.
لأنّها حطّمت فوسوي مارو
Wasn't it you who put a marble under the Fusui-maru
ألم تكن من وضع الكرة الرخامية أسفل فوسوي مارو
to make it easy to fall?
لتسهيل سقوطه؟
To make this murder look like a suicide that she committed
لجعل هذه الجريمة تبدو انتحاراً أقدمت عليه
because of her own mishandling of things?!
بسبب إخفاقها في حمل الآنية؟
I get it.
فهمت
If she was in charge of selling these works,
،إذا كانت هي المسؤولة عن بيع القطع
she would've been the one who stored and removed them here.
فهي من يخزّنها هنا ويخرجها غالباً
So she was bound to drop it eventually.
فكان حتميّاً أن تسقطه بنهاية المطاف
Moreover, she fell asleep drunk during the party.
كما أنّها نامت من الثمالة أثناء الحفلة
Last night was the perfect chance.
كانت البارحة الفرصة المثاليّة
Please knock this off! You shouldn't blame me without any proof...
توقّف رجاءً! لا يمكنك إلقاء التهمّة عليّ ...دون امتلاك دليل
Actually, I believe you're still wearing the proof.
أليس الدليل على شيءٍ ترتديه بالفعل؟
Now then, Inspector! Please lift up the back of his jacket!
حسناً حضرة المفتّش، ارفع معطفه من على ظهره رجاءً
What's this?!
!هذا؟
Lipstick?!
أ-أحمر شفاه؟
That most likely got there while you were carrying her up the shelf.
وصله عندما كان يحمل السيّدة للرفّ على الأرجح
You'd have to carry her on your shoulders to use the ladder, after all.
لا يمكنك صعود السلّم دون حملها على كتفيك
And then you returned to the stateroom, as if nothing had happened.
ثمّ رجعت لغرفة المعيشة كما لو أنّ شيئاً لم يحصل
You had left the party to carry her here before she sobered up!
غادرت الحفلة لنقلها هناك !قبل أن تصحو من ثملها
Have a look at the sitting cushions in the stateroom.
انظروا لوسادات الجلوس في غرفة المعيشة
One has a bit of the lipstick he brought back with him.
على إحداها أحمر الشفاه الذي انتقل منه
But maybe she just happened to touch my back
لكن ربما نقلته لظهري مصادفةً
while she was sleeping during the party.
بينما كانت نائمةً أثناء الحفلة
I was drunk last night, so I don't really remember,
كنتُ ثملاً البارحة، فلا أتذكّر بوضوح
but can you say that isn't a possibility?
لكن أيمكنك إنكار هذه الاحتماليّة؟
You leave me no choice then. I'll show my trump card.
لا تترك لي خياراً إذاً، سأريك دليلي الخاص
Hey, Conan! Show 'em what you found.
كونان! هات ذاك الشيء الذي وجدته
C-Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن؟
Here it is, mister!
!ها هو يا عمّ، صحيح؟
Conan-kun! That's dangerous!
!كونان-كن! هذا خطر
Huh?
ماذا؟
W-What the--?!
...هـ-هذا
A cell phone!
!هاتف خلويّ؟
What's this doing inside a pot?!
!لمَ يوجد داخل الإناء؟
To make sure this murder worked as planned.
كان للتحقّق من نجاح الجريمة
Even if she was atop a narrow shelf,
،حتّى لو كانت مستلقيةً على رفٍّ ضيّق
there'd be no guarantee she'd lose her balance.
لا ضمان لفقدانها توازنها عند استيقاظها
But it'd be a different story if a phone under her pillow rang.
لكن سيختلف الموضوع إذا رنّ الهاتف أسفل وسادتها
In that situation, most people would reach out without thinking.
سيمدّ الجميع أيديهم بلا تفكير في ذاك الوضع غالباً
Even more so if she used her cell phone as an alarm clock.
خصوصاً لو كانوا يستعملون هاتفهم كساعة تنبيه مثل السيّدة
Yes. Seto-san placed that pot in the shelf directly under her
أجل، وضع سيتو-سان ذاك الإناء في الرفّ أسفلها تماماً
Checking the cell phone's number should make it immediately clear
تفقّد رقم هذا الهاتف الخلويّ سيكشف فوراً
that it belongs to Seto-san.
أنّه يخصّ سيتو-سان
Tell me, detective. How did you know it was me?
أخبرني حضرة المتحرّي، كيف عرفت أنّه أنا؟
Yes, I made the call. But Otani could have too when he left the room!
صحيحٌ أنّي أجريت الاتّصال، لكن كان بإمكان أوتاني الذي غادر الغرفة أيضاً فعل ذلك
That's right.
صحيح
I thought so too when Conan found the pot with the phone in it.
فكّرتُ بالأمر عندما وجد كونان الإناء الذي يحوي الهاتف
Then how?!
!كيف إذاً؟
After all, when you tried to call her, you said this:
:عندما اتّصلت بها، قلتَ التالي
That's strange. She's not answering.
غريب، إنّها لا تجيب
But her cell phone had been turned off when it was found.
لكن هاتفها الخلويّ كان مُطفأً عندما عُثر عليه
The cell phone was apparently turned off.
يبدو أنّ الهاتف الخلويّ كان مُطفأً
In such cases, a cell phone would reply
في تلك الحالة، كان ليكون ردّ الهاتف الخلويّ
by saying that it is either turned off or out of signal range.
أنّه مُطفأ، أو خارج نطاق الإرسال
My suspicion was confirmed once I remembered that.
تيقّنتُ بعدما تذكّرتُ ذلك
My suspicion that when you called, you called a different number.
كنتَ قد اتّصلت برقمٍ آخر آنذاك
I see. I guess I should've said I couldn't get through to her phone.
فهمت، كان عليّ قول أنّي لا أستطيع الوصول لهاتفها إذاً
But I can't believe you'd destroy Master's Fusui-maru to kill her!
لكن لا أستطيع تصديق أنّك قتلتها !وحطّمت فوسوي مارو الخاصّ بالمعلّم لذلك
That thing can turn to dust for all I care.
ولو تحطّم ذاك الشيء لأشلاء، فلا يعنيني
After all, it's a counterfeit copy I made of the real Fusui-maru.
فهو قطعة مزيّفة صنعتها بتقليد فوسوي مارو الحقيقيّ
C-Counterfeit?!
!قـ-قطعة مزيّفة؟
Yeah. The real one is stored in a different location.
أجل، الحقيقيّة محفوظة في مكانٍ آخر
Still, even though it broke, to think I could fool even her eyes...
لكن، نجاحي في خداع أعين السيّدة ...رغم أنّه تحطّم أمامها
My skill has really come far.
هذا يثبت أنّ مهارتي تحسّنت
Though that's why she sold my works for high prices, of course.
رغم أنّها تمكّنت من بيع أعمالي بأسعار باهظة لهذا السبب
H-High prices?!
!أ-أسعار باهظة؟
You don't mean--?!
...أتقصد
Yeah.
أجل
She took my works and sold them to rich, artistic know-nothings,
،أخذت أعمالي وباعتها لأثرياء سُذّج جاهلين
claiming they were Master's works!
!مدّعية أنّها من صنع المعلّم
W-What?!
!ماذا؟
By the time I realized it, she had already sold several dozen.
بوقت إدراكي ذلك، كانت قد باعت عدّة عشرات
I questioned her about it, of course,
،،،واجهتُها بذلك بالطبع
but she not only didn't apologize...
...لكنّها، ناهيك عن عدم الاعتذار
You should be thankful more than anything.
يجدر بك الامتنان
I'm actually selling the unoriginal junk that you make!
فأنا أنجح في بيع الخرد غير الأصليّة اللي تصنعها
Wait, does that mean your recent slump was--?
...أيعني ذلك أنّ هبوط مستواك مؤخراً
Yeah! It was on purpose!
!أجل، كان مقصوداً
I didn't want to harm Master's name any further...
!لم أرد تشويه اسم المعلّم أكثر
But she threatened to kick me out if I didn't keep making stuff!
!لكنّها هددتني بطردي إذا توقّفت عن صنع الأواني
I couldn't put up with it anymore, so...
...لم أستطع تحمّل ذلك أكثر، فقرّرت
Y-You fool!
!يا-يا أحمق
Why didn't you tell Master about it?! Surely he--
...لمَ لم تخبر المعلّم بهذا الأمر؟ كان حتماً لـ
I couldn't.
لم أستطع
I couldn't tell him my fakes sold for more than his authentic works...
كيف أخبره أنّ قطعي المزيّفة قد بِيعت بثمن أعلى من أعماله الأصليّة؟
Let's go.
هيّا بنا
I don't know. It doesn't seem that valuable to me...
...بصراحة، لا يبدو بذاك المستوى لي
Appearances don't always match what's on the inside.
المظاهر لا تطابق المضمون دوماً
Hot!
!ساخن
Gotcha!
!دعابة
In his case, his appearance does match what's on the inside...
في حالته، المظهر يطابق المضمون
First love?
!حُب أوّل؟
Crap!
!هذا سيّئ
Asami-senpai was Shinichi's first love?
كانت حُبّ شينتشي الأوّل؟
The villa is on fire!
!النزل يحترق
No way!
!لا يمكن
But she's still inside...
!لا تزال أسامي سينباي هناك
Senpai!
!سينباي
On the next Conan: "The Memories of First Love Case (Part 1)."
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Lemon pie.
فطيرة بالليمون
What does your first love taste like?
للحلقة القادمة، أيّ مذاق يتبادر لك عندما تفكّر بالحبّ الأوّل؟
Eel bowls.
!علبة غداء أنقليس
Seriously?
...مهلك